{
    "id": "f2be1b1bb50446da9dd8619300fca171",
    "title": "Direct And Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Ramesh said that he ....................... his homework.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "has finished",
                "had finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c12b3c12329148c3a0c94533ae4efe09"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy asked his mother ....................... he could watch TV.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "that",
                "weather"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4db89d3a882645edbb7d4542fc066e4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked the passerby if he ....................... help him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ce47a6ef29764aadbfca43fac7cc43e6"
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl said that I ........................ on her seat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am sitting",
                "was sitting",
                "have been sitting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "756a4b480fae405fb231db277842bfcb"
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked the boy where ........................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was he going",
                "he was going",
                "was going he"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bccbbced44054a30bf77fc6dd0364f43"
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl asked who ......................... her pen.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have taken",
                "had taken",
                "would take"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ca1653fe93794703b865145e458db98b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher advised the students ..................... hard.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to work",
                "working",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "315d1074a13149f08eba571bb477a3be"
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother told the boy ..................... there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to wait",
                "waiting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "59816d8c4ac648cca6decdf627e009fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "The manager asked the clerk ........................... that file to the secretary.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to take",
                "taking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1209aaffb781421686620f0e59b642a9"
        },
        {
            "question": "The old man asked me if I ...................... help him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e5d71023dc74b079a3cec4fd8694138"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ramesh said that he ...................... John the previous day.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have seen",
                "had seen",
                "would see"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f1f802b5e33446cb8e6e4fcdf1798341"
        }
    ]
}